妈 那狗又在吠
Mom. The dog again.
听到了 宝贝 我想掐死那条疯老狗
I know baby. I want to strangle that crazy old thing.
别理它就是了
Just ignore it.
对你来说确实容易
It's easy for you to ignore
因为你已经老耳闭塞
because you have the old-man hearing.
但是我跟曼尼有着朝气蓬勃的双耳
But Manny and I -- we have the young ears.
我就不明白你怎么会受不了一条咆哮狗
I don't get how one dog keeps you awake
你老家满街都是斗鸡和武装革命
when you grew up sleeping through
应该早习惯了吧
cockfights and revolutions.
很好笑 杰
Mm-hmm. Very funny, Jay.
曼尼已经好几个礼拜都没睡好觉了
Manny hasn't been able to sleep in weeks.
他都没精神上课
It's screwing his brain for school.
那狗吠个不停
And it doesn't stop.
一直不停地叫啊叫啊叫啊叫啊叫啊叫啊
It goes on and on and on and on and on and on
-叫啊叫啊 -行了 这声挺烦的
- and on and on and on. - Yes, that could be annoying.
我受够了 我去找他们
That's it. I'm going over there.
歌洛莉亚 别惹事
Gloria, now, don't go starting something
因为不管你干什么 最后还不是我善后
because whenever you do, I'm the one that --
这声她倒是可以不理会
That she couldn't hear.
他们都不见了 小卡
They're gone. Cam.
所有的小孩都不见了
All the children are gone.
什么孩子们
What children?
我在公园跑步
I was running in the park,
然后我发现
and I noticed that none of the kids
跟莉莉一起玩的小孩都不见了
Lily usually plays with were there.
-现在还早着呢 -但是我遇到了罗莉
- Well, it's still early. - But then I ran into Lori.
大胸罗莉还是牙套罗莉
Boobs Lori or adult-braces Lori?
-美鞋罗莉 -我喜欢她
- Great-shoes Lori. - Oh, I like her.
她说他们都把孩子送去上幼儿园了
And she said that they all sent their kids to preschool.
什么 我们说好了明年再上的
What?! We agreed to wait till next year.
那是忽悠我们 好给自家孩子争取名额
It was a fake-out to make sure that their kids got a spot.
那些瘦婊子
Those skinny bitches.
我们必须去报名 卡梅隆
We have got to get her into school, Cameron,
不然她就落后了
or else she's gonna fall behind.
你以为我不知道吗
Don't you think I know that?
真够绝的
This is perfect.
让那对基佬
Oh, leave it to the gays
养出美利坚唯一一个成绩烂的亚洲小孩吧
to raise the only underachieving Asian in America.
好了 这个给你
Okay, here you go.
伙计们 吃早餐了
Guys, breakfast.
伙计们 菲尔 理我一下
Guys. Phil. Hello.
我在我在
Totally with you.
孩子们 盘子放到洗碗机里去
Kids, put your dishes in the dishwasher.
好了 我受够了
Okay, no. That's it.
每个人都给老娘把手里的玩意儿放下
Everybody, gadgets down now!
你干嘛发飙
Why are you freaking out?
因为这些玩意把你们魂都勾跑了
Because you're all so involved with your little gizmos,
都没人讲话了
nobody is even talking.
家人彼此间应该交流
Families are supposed to talk.
你在处理什么了不得的事吗
What are you doing that's so important?
我在捣鼓俺的梦幻烤炉
Oh, I'm locking in my fantasy roster.
我战无不胜
I'm unbeatable.
我们正要建一个地上泳池
We're totally getting an aboveground pool.
去死吧 蠢货 去死吧
Die, stupid, die!
卢克 我叫你把那东西放下
Luke, I told you to put that down now.
快点 小子
Come on, buddy.
等一下 我就要破老爸的记录了
One second. I'm about to beat dad's record.
听妈妈的话
You heard your mother.
有什么这么好笑
What is so funny?
没什么
Nothing.
"老妈疯了" 谢谢 海莉
"Mom's insane." Thank you, Haley.
至少我们在交流
At least we talk.
喂
Hello.
是我 哪所幼儿园比较好
Hey, it's me. What's a good preschool?
我家小孩去的是沃根威尔
Uh, well, our kids went to Wagon Wheel.
那所好吗 你喜欢吗
And it was good? You liked it?
你知道我的小孩
Oh, well, you know my kids
反正也都不是什么太好的胚子
are middle-management material at best.
也不想在他们身上浪费太多钱
Didn't want to waste a lot of money --
米奇尔 那所不赖
Yes, Mitchell, it's good.
干吗突然问这个
Why the interest?
我突然发现莉莉的玩伴们
I just realized that all of Lily's friends
今年都上幼儿园了 她现在落后了
are going to school this year, and now she's late.
别担心 她可以明年再上
Don't worry. She can wait another year.
给她买部黑莓手机就是了
Just buy her a Blackberry,
反正现在的小孩就爱它
that's all she's gonna want to do anyway.
她说什么
What did she say?
她说给莉莉买部黑莓手机
She says to buy her a Blackberry.
莉莉的小手还没法玩手机呢 克莱尔
Lily doesn't have the dexterity for that, Claire!
她疯了吧
What is happening?
你能不能问一下你那间学校
Can you just check with your school
看看能不能接收我们
and see if maybe you can get us in?
我也许可以帮你安排一次会面
Hmm. I-I can probably get you an interview.
太棒了 太好了
Oh, no. That's great. That's great.
谢谢 真的太感谢了
Thank you. I really appreciate it.
还有 顺便问一下 你觉得
Oh, and, by the way, what do you think
比林斯利学院怎么样
of that place Billingsley Academy?
比林斯利 拽得很呢
Ooh. Billingsley. Very hoity-toity.
一般人根本进不去 除非你富得流油
You can't get in there unless you're really rich
或者在校董会有人
or you know somebody on the board.
天啊 这简直是个噩梦
Oh, god, this is a nightmare.
米奇 幼儿园罢了 别小题大做
Mitch, it's preschool. Don't overthink it.
我家小孩也没上比林斯利
My kids didn't go to Billingsley,
他们不也好好的吗
and they are fine.
我得挂了
I have to go.
菲尔
Phil.
有创意
That's awesome.
-早上好 -你好
- Buenos dias. - Hi.
我们还没正式见过面
We haven't formally met.
我是住在隔壁的歌洛莉亚·普里契特
I'm Gloria Pritchett from next door.
我叫拉瑞·保森 见过面了
Larry Paulson. Yeah, I've seen you. Mm.
艳福不浅啊
Lucky guy.
是福是祸你很快就知道了
Wait a minute, then tell me.
你的狗吠个不停
Your dog doesn't stop barking.
整日整夜乱吠
All morning, all night.
他吵醒了我儿子
He wakes my son up,
他需要充足的睡眠
and he needs his sleep.
不是我的狗 是我即将散伙的妻子的
It's not my dog. It's my soon-to-be ex-wife's.
她三个星期前搬出去了
She moved out three weeks ago.
她会回来取吗
Is she coming back for it?
除非狗屎变美钞
Not unless it starts crapping money.
那你必须想办法治治它
Well, you need to do something about the dog.
那狗又老又笨
The dog is old and stupid.
你到底是在生谁的气 拉瑞
Who are you really mad at, Larry?
那条狗还是你妻子
The dog or your wife?
这小孩怎么回事
Who the hell is this kid?
别扯上小孩
Hey, there's no need for that.
我告诉你他是怎么回事
I'll tell you who he is.
他的名字就叫做 让你那该死的狗闭嘴
His name is "shut up your damn dog"!
真是讽刺至极啊
You know what's ironic?
我从来都没有抱怨过
And I have never once said a word
你们家那只聒噪的鹦鹉
About that obnoxious parrot of yours
叫声简直非人类
That's always squawking.
鹦鹉
Parrot?
什么鹦鹉
What parrot?
杰
Jay!
他那是什么意思 哪儿来的鹦鹉
What is he talking about? What parrot?
我怎么知道
How the hell do I know?
那我们现在应该怎么做
So, what do we do now?
我们已经和他说了 还能做什么
Nothing. We did it. He heard us.
但他什么都没听进去
He didn't hear nothing.
杰 别走 杰
Jay, don't go. Jay!
杰 杰
Jay! Jay!
好了 我们召开这次家庭会议的原因是
Okay, we have called this family meeting
个人电子产品已经影响了正常生活
Because the personal electronics have gotten out of control.
从今天起 将进行为期一周的电子设备禁用周
Starting today, there's going to be a one-week ban
-禁止用手机 发信息 -噢不
-On all cellphones, texting, -oh!
禁止上论坛 视屏聊天 玩游戏
Im'ing, video chatting, video-gaming,
-禁止任何网络行为 -那我该怎么做作业
-Anything on the internet. -How am I supposed to do my homework?
跟我学学
The way I did.
拿一个凿子和一块石头
With a chisel and a piece of stone.
-菲尔 -别想阻止我发自内心的幽默感
-Phil. -Can't unplug my funny bone.
我马上就要完成一份科学论文
I have a huge science paper due.
别担心 也许家里还有本祖传的百科全书
And we have a great set of encyclopedias...Somewhere.
不然你认为公共图书馆是用来干吗
What do you think the public library is for?
我以为那里是流浪汉的免费公厕
I thought that was a bathroom for homeless people.
我还能继续玩植物大战僵尸吗
Can I still play plants vs. Zombies?
你是不是聋了
Are you not listening?
-但是你了解植物 -怎么
-But you learn about plants. -Mm-hmm.
植物是有生命的
And plants are life.
难道你反对生命吗
Are you against life?
那我该怎么和我的朋友聊天
How am I supposed to talk to my friends?
在学校聊个痛快
Talk to them at school.
或者在果汁店
Or at a juice bar.
或者用座机打
Or on the house phone.
没人知道我们家的号码
Nobody even knows our number.
连我自己都不知道
I don't even know our number.
这么说老爸也不会再去上网咯
So, you're saying dad's not going to go online?
-当然 -老爸
-Yep. -Dad?
-是的 -那疯狂足球怎么办
-That's right. -What about fantasy football?
不用担心 球队那边已经都安排好了
Not a problem. My team's set this week.
我至死不渝地
I am completely on board
支持你老妈的突发奇想
your mother's horse and buggy to yesteryear.
接下来的一周 我要回归原始社会
For the next week, I may as well be Amish.
原始人邓菲
Jebediah Dunphy.
穴居狩猎 茹毛饮血
Raising barns, witnessing murders,
钻木取火
Making electric fireplace hearths.
这简直太不公平了
Oh! This is so unfair!
你猜怎么着
You know what?
我们可以搞得有趣些
We're gonna make this fun.
把它当作一次比赛
Turn it into a game.
坚持到最后的那个人就是胜利者
Whoever stays unplugged the longest, wins.
菲尔 这不是我的初衷
Not what I had in mind, Phil.
-我们能赢得什么 -你们想要什么
-What do we win? -What do you want?
我想要一台新电脑
I want a new computer.
成
Done
我们禁止他们用电子产品
We're gonna get them off of electronics
结果却要给他们添置更多电子设备吗
with the promise of more electronics?
-我想要鸡肉馅饼 -整只鸡都行
-I want chicken pot pie. -And chicken.
我想要一辆车
I want a car.
-没门 -成
-No way! -Done!
我能有自己的车了
Yeah, I'm getting a car!
-没错 很有趣 对吧 -菲尔
-Yeah, fun, right? -Phil!
我们养不起第三辆车
We cannot afford a third car.
别担心 他们不可能赢我们
Relax. They're never gonna last as long as us.
亲爱的 别误会
Oh, honey, don't take this the wrong way,
但我确实对你没有任何信心
but I have almost no faith in you.
乔安妮马上就会出来
Joanie will be right out.
她马上就会结束那个接见
She's just finishing up another interview.
好的 谢谢 谢谢 谢谢
Okay. Thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
-不客气 -我真心喜欢这个地方
- You're welcome. - I really like this place.
-看看这些画 -我看到了
- Look at all these drawings. - I know.
你看到院子里的鸭鸭了吗
And did you see the duckies in the yard?
-莉莉最喜欢鸭鸭了 -我知道
- Lily loves duckies. - I know.
我等会要提到这些
I'm gonna mention that.
行啊 说啊
Okay, well, do,
搞的好像说这个就能让她显得与众不同似的
because that's really gonna set her apart from the rest of the kids.
我们还要提到
We should also mention
当我们看克莱尔· 罗斯的 脱口秀时 她总是很兴奋
how she always perks up when we watch "Charlie Rose."
就一次而已 因为当时他在采访艾摩
That was one time. He was interviewing Elmo.
你们放轻松点
You boys ought to relax.
对不起
Oh, I'm sorry.
-我们只是想留下一个好印象 -对的
- We just -- we really want to make a good impression. - Mm.
基佬养父母加上一个外籍宝宝
Gay adoptive parents with a minority baby?
学校随你们挑
Sugars, you can get into any school you want.
什么 真的吗
What was that? Really?
你们不知道吗
Oh, you didn't know that?
当然
oh, yeah.
所有的学校都爱吹嘘自己没有任何歧视
All of these schools like to brag about their diversity.
你们简直是神奇三侠啊
You're diverse times three.
绝对供不应求
In demand.
你们简直就像热卖的音乐会门票
You're like Jimmy Buffett tickets
那些非同白人完全不是你们的对手
to these hybrid-driving, straight white folks.
多谢夸奖 小妞
I hear that, girl.
好吧
Yeah.
我来啦 别急
I'm coming!
我家的狗在哪
Where the hell is the dog?
-是谁在敲门 -我们的邻居
-Who is it? -It's our neighbor.
我家的狗不见了
The dog is gone.
也许它自个跑走了
Maybe it ran away.
有链子锁着呢 怎么跑
It was chained to a tree.
也许你老婆带走了
Maybe your wife took it.
根据我的信用卡账单 我老婆人在欧洲
According to my credit card, my wife is in europe,
正在搜寻最豪华的酒店
searching for the world's most expensive hotel.
那关我们什么事
Then what do you want from us?
你来我家抱怨狗吵
You come over complaining about the dog
然后第二天我家的狗就不见了
And the next day it's gone?
你说我来干什么
You tell me.
-我会... -居然敢来这里撒野
-I'll tell -- -how dare you?
你到我们家来 把我们家的门铃都要按爆了
You come to our house, you ring our bell many times,
还指责我们绑了你的狗
And you accuse us of taking your dog.
慢走不送
You should go home.
-这事还没完呢 -不 已经说的很清楚了
-We're not done here. -Yes, we are.
你到底做了什么
What did you do?
你肯定不想知道的
You don't want to know.
歌洛莉亚的祖父和叔叔们都是屠夫
Gloria's grandfather and uncles were butchers,
所以一说到杀戮
so she's always had a certain comfort level
她总是习以为常
when it comes to...Killing.
有一次 我们家闹耗子
One time, we had this rat...
首先拍烂它
What? First you smash it,
然后砍断鼠头
then you cut the head off.
她就像孙二娘转世
It was like nothing to her.
我要去教堂了
I go to church now.
她把鼠头留在那儿
She left the head out there
杀一儆百
To send a message to the other rats.
-嗨 -嗨 亲爱的
- Hey. - Hi, honey.
今天工作顺利不
How was your day at work?
棒极了
Amazing. Mwah.
哇 说说看
Great. What happened?
没有像平常那样 把午休时间浪费在上网啊
Instead of wasting my lunch hour surfing the web,
查足球动态啊之类的
checking football stats,
今天我在舒缓的音乐伴奏下
I put on some mellow music,
冥思静想
and I meditated.
哇 坚持了多久
Wow. For how long?
我也不知多久 反正我二十分钟前刚醒
I have no idea. I just woke up 20 minutes ago.
妈
Hey, mom.
我们美术课作业要用一块肥皂和一根黑色马克笔
I need a bar of soap and a black marker for an art project.
好的 马克笔在那儿
Okay. Well, the marker's over there,
肥皂在水池下面
and the soap is under the sink.
你看只要你不沉迷于网络
Isn't it great how much time you have
就能省出大把时间啊
now that you're not wasting it online?
老天 你一直都这么说话吗
Oh, my god. Is this what you always sound like?
老爸 看看我建了什么 邓菲之塔
Look what I built, dad. Dunphy towers.
二百间公寓 每间都住了一个幸福的家庭
200 condos, a happy family in every one.
不错啊 小伙
Way to go, buddy.
亲爱的 我真佩服你
I got to hand it to you, honey.
24小时没玩游戏
24 hours without video games,
他都开始造福社会了
he's already contributing to society.
去死吧 去死吧
Die! Die!
老师说 他已经分不清梦境和现实了
To be fair, he's using his imagination.
没有安全出口
There's no fire escapes!
他们抄近路了
They cut corners!
我来灭了你们
I'll cut your corners!
喂
Hello?
哦 嗨 卢克小宝贝 找你的
Oh, hi. Luke, honey, it's for you.
嗨 格里芬 你好吗
Hi, Griffin. How are you?
嗯 他在这儿 稍等
Yeah, he's right here. Hold on.
喂 格里芬
Hey, Griffin.
-哦 天哪 -怎么了
- Oh, my God! - What happened?
Youtube上有个驴在水上滑翔的视频
There's a parasailing-donkey video on Youtube.
哦 天哪
Oh, my god!
等等 卢克 比赛怎么办
Wait, Luke. What about the contest?
我退出
I quit.
我可不是石头人
I'm not made of stone, you know.
恶 难以置信
Uhh! I can't believe it.
我论文居然拿了个"B"
I got a "B" on my paper.
-恭喜 -不错哦
- Good for you. - Yeah.
不 对你们来说可能不错
No, it would be good for you.
对我简直糟糕透顶
It's terrible for me.
多谢你那发了霉的百科全书
Thanks to your moldy encyclopedias,
我对有丝分裂的描述完全过时了
my take on mitosis was completely out of date.
甚至都没人用原生质这种说法了
They don't even call it protoplasm anymore.
现在都叫细胞质
It's cytoplasm.
你可以问我们的呀
Well, you could have asked one of us.
你在搞笑吗
Now you're making jokes?
-我没在搞笑 -真的吗
- I'm not making a joke. - Really?
生殖细胞和受精卵的区别是什么
What's the difference between a gamete and a zygote?
别上当 克莱尔
Don't fall for it, Claire.
她瞎编了俩单词
She's just making up words.
够了
That's it.
我需要因特网
I need the internet.
我退出你们的烂比赛
I'm out of your stupid contest.
三强争霸
And then there were three.
她杀气十足
She's kind of scary.
我们才不会给她买车
We're not buying her a car.
小伙儿 看啥呢
Hey, buddy, what you reading?
《老人与海》
"The old man and the sea."
喜欢吗
You like it?
我喜欢海明威的开门见山
I like that Hemingway gets to the point.
你读过他另外的作品啊
You read a lot of his stuff?
我是在暗示你有话就说 杰
That was a hint, Jay.
哦 明白
Oh, okay.
我想问你点事
I want to ask you something...
天知地知 你知我知
between you and me.
你想知道我妈有没有
You want to know if I think my mom
对那狗下毒手
did something to that dog.
-对 -坐
- Yeah. - Sit.
小孩一般都喝汽水的吧
Don't most kids drink soda?
谁管他们喝什么
Who knows what they do?
回归正题
So, your mom.
杰 这十二年来我学会了几件事
Jay, I've learned a few things in my 12 years.
亚麻衣服别买地摊货
Don't skimp on linens,
千万不要赞美老师的身材
don't compliment a teacher on her figure,
至于我妈
and when it comes to my mom,
有些问题你还是别问了 我也不想知道答案
never ask questions I don't want the answers to.
我才不信 你这么敏感的小孩儿
I don't buy it. Sensitive kid like you.
肯定跟我一样 有打破沙锅探到底的精神
I think you want to know every bit as much as I do.
你错了
You're wrong.
那你手怎么发抖了
Then why is your hand shaking?
这是我今天第五杯咖啡
This is my fifth one of these today.
我可能咖啡喝太多了
I may have a problem.
好吧 别喝了
Okay. That's enough.
不不不 明天下午四点非常好
No, no, no, 4:00 tomorrow is fine.
好的 那么我和我的伴侣与您到时见
Yeah, my life partner and I will see you then.
谢谢您
Thank -- thank you.
什么时候起你开始管我叫伴侣了
Since when do you call me your life partner?
从我们拿到了比林斯利学园的面试名额起
Since a spot opened up at Billingsley Academy.
但我喜欢沃根威尔 那里有好多小鸭鸭
But I liked Wagon Wheel. It had all the duckies.
这让我回忆起我在密苏里童年时光
And it reminded me of where I went in Missouri.
小卡 比林斯利可不是浪得虚名
Cam, everyone goes to Billingsley for a reason --
它就相当于学前班中的哈佛
It's the Harvard of preschools.
她还不到两岁呢
She's not even 2 years old yet.
她不需要什么哈佛学前班
She doesn't need the Harvard of Preschools.
她需要的是手指画和小鸭鸭
She needs finger painting and duckies.
我求你了 你就不能说"鸭子"吗
I'm begging you to please just say "Ducks."
喂
Hello?
好消息 沃根威尔很欣赏你们
Great news. Wagon Wheel loved you.
-你们进了 -哦
- You're in. - Oh.
沃根威尔要咱们
Wagon Wheel wants us.
哦 太棒了
Oh, yes!
这真是个好消息
Okay. Well, that's great and everything,
不过我们明天还要去赶另一个入学面试
but actually we have an appointment tomorrow
-比林斯利小学 -真的吗
- At Billingsley. - Really?
没错 显然我们很抢手
Yeah, apparently we are in very high demand.
只是要你知道 我觉得沃根威尔
Oh, well, just so you know, I don't think Wagon Wheel
不会给你们当备胎
is gonna hold a place for you.
我觉得我们这回得碰碰运气
Well, I think we're gonna take our chance.
碰运气 听起来真不靠谱
Take our chance? That sounds chancy.
米奇尔
You know, Mitchell,
是你惊慌失措地给我打电话
you were the one who called me in a panic.
是你叫我帮忙报上名
You were the one who needed me to get you in.
我很抱歉 克莱尔
I'm sorry, Claire.
我不是有意麻烦你的
I didn't mean to put you out.
但你也别说得这么夸张
But let's not get too dramatic here.
不过就是写了封邮件而已
You wrote an e-mail.
这不是封邮件
It wasn't an e-mail.
是一通有线电话
It was a phone call from a land line.
你做了什么
What did you do?
-是为莉莉好 -是吗
- What's best for Lily. - Did you?
小卡 这是我们作为基佬头一回
Cam, this is the first time that being gay
享受到竞争优势
is a competitive advantage.
他们体操班正在招人
They're choosing teams for gym class,
我们终于能首批入选
and we're finally getting picked first.
我一直都是最先被选上
I always got picked first.
因为我能用躲避球砸穿一层夹板
I could throw a dodgeball through a piece of plywood.
不过我懂你意思
But I see your point.
别像鬼一样靠近我
Don't sneak up on me like that.
你出来这儿干什么
What are you doing out here?
你来问我妈的事搞得我头都大了
You got in my head about my mom.
这就是杀鼠之铲吗
Is that the rat shovel?
没错
Yeah.
你在找狗狗的线索吗
Are you checking it for signs of dog?
我正准备检查
I was going to.
我们速战速决
Well, let's do this quick.
要是被她抓住的话
If she catches us,
我们就跟这狗一样死定了
we're as dead as that dog probably is.
-你们在这儿干嘛呢 -什么也没干
- What are you doing here? - Nothing.
你们干嘛看这个铲子
Why are you looking at that shovel?
你觉得有人
Do you think someone
用这铲子干了什么事吗 曼尼
did something with that shovel, Manny?
他认为是你杀了那只狗
He thinks you killed the dog.
你这鼠辈
You little rat.
别叫我老鼠
Don't call me a rat!
她是灭鼠天后
She kills rats!
你真的认为是我杀了那只狗吗
You really think that I would kill a dog?
那我该怎么想
Well, what was I supposed to think?
我不知道
I don't know.
我没杀那只狗怎么样
How about I didn't kill a dog?
那就告诉我你把它怎么了
Just tell me what you did with it.
他去了一个更好的地方
He's in a better place.
人们说什么东西死了的时候都这么说
That's what people say when something's dead.
好吧
Okay, fine.
我把它带去了一个农场
I took him to a farm
那里地方很大任由它玩耍
where he has plenty of room to run.
人们说什么东西死了的第二种表述方式
That's the second thing people say when something's dead.
我专属美发师的兄弟有三个孩子
My hairdresser's brother has three kids.
他们住在乡下
They live in the country.
他们很高兴拥有这只狗
They were so happy to have the dog
还送给我们一瓶咸菜
that they gave me a jar of pickles.
这也是人们说什么东西死了的一种方式吗
Is that also what they say when something is dead?
真的吗
Really?
看 看看他们多么开心
Look. Look how happy they are,
而不是在这儿孤零零地
instead of him being tied to a tree outside
被绑在外面的树上
with no one to talk to.
你怎么不一开始告诉我这些
Why didn't you just tell me this in the first place?
就好像你不在意我偷一只狗似的
Like you would be okay with me stealing a dog?
-当然不行 -就是这样
- No. - Exactly.
这就是我不告诉你的原因
That's why I didn't tell you.
现在狗狗开心 曼尼能安心睡觉
Now the dog is happy, Manny can sleep,
而我们还有咸菜吃
and we have pickles.
好的 这次的事就这么算了
Okay, it worked out this time,
不过别忘了偷窃是违法的
but don't forget that stealing is against the law.
-也许在哥伦比亚 -又来了
- Now, maybe in Colombia. - Ah, here we go,
因为在哥伦比亚我们会被羊绊倒
because in Colombia we trip over goats
我们当街杀人
and we kill people in the street.
你知道这有多伤人吗
Do you know how offensive that is?
就好像我们是秘鲁人似的
Like we are Peruvians!
这比赛太难熬了
The contest was hard.
预定
Reservations.
虽然我们发誓断绝网络
Even though we had sworn off the internet,
但是外面的人没有
the rest of the world hadn't.
奥兰多
Orlando.
国内的
Domestic.
代理人
Representative.
Representative!
代理人 代理人
Representative! Representative!
你有一封邮件
You've got mail.
-真的假的 克莱尔 -你不明白
- Really, Claire? - You don't understand.
我正试着买机票
I was trying to deal with our plane tickets
去拜访你的家人
to visit your family.
别说了 你这是自找难堪
Please stop. You're just embarrassing yourself.
巅峰对决 老头
Well, it looks like it's just you and me, old man.
放马过来吧
Bring it.
终于 我们逛回办公室了
And finally, here we are back at the office.
你们如果愿意坐一会的话
If you two would like to take a seat,
我这就去通知普林普顿先生说你们到了
I will let Mr. Plympton know that you're here.
-谢谢你 -好的 谢谢你
- Thank you. - Yes, thank you.
这地方太赞了
This place is amazing!
我早就告诉你了
I told you.
就像霍格沃茨一样
It's like Hogwarts!
瓢虫避难所
The ladybug sanctuary.
我的天啊 还有那些小鹅卵石
Oh, my gosh. The little cobblestones.
太可爱了 我知道
So sweet. I know.
去他的鸭鸭吧 我们属于这里
Screw the duckies. We belong here.
你觉得他们会收我们吗
Do you think they're gonna let us in?
小卡 放松一下
Cam, relax.
基佬就是好 学校任我挑
We're queer, we're here.
没错 对极了
Yes, we are.
好了 再等几分钟
Okay. Just a few more minutes.
谢谢
Thank you.
是的 谢谢
Yes, thank you.
你好 我是斯蒂芬妮·卡莱尔
Hi. I'm Stephanie Kaner.
这是加佛
And this is Javar.
我们和普林普顿先生约好有个面试
We have an interview with Mr. Plympton.
真好 这两位先来 你是下一个
Wonderful. These two are first. You'll be next.
单身白人母亲 黑人小孩
Single white mother, black child.
那又怎样
So what?
莉莉是亚洲宝宝 我们是基佬
Lily's asian. We're gay.
在这场入学扑克赛中
In the school admissions poker game,
我们可是一手好牌
we're the winning hand.
亲爱的 不好意思
Oh, honey, sorry.
这是我的伴侣卡维塔
My partner Kavita.
你好 很高兴见到你
Hi. Nice to meet you.
Hello. Nice to meet you.
再等几分钟
It will be just a few minutes.
跨种族的残疾拉拉带着一个非洲娃娃
Disabled interracial lesbians with an african kicker.
始料未及
Did not see that coming.
我已经有段时间没看纸质报纸了
It's been a while since I read an actual newspaper.
真怀念那声音啊
Miss that sound.
-不会吧 不会吧 -怎么啦
- No, no, no, no! - What is it?
布拉德受伤了
Brady's injured.
别这样啊 他是整支队伍的灵魂人物
No! He's my whole team.
看来我得修改队员名单了
I have to change my roster.
亲爱的 如果你在电话上不能搞定的话
Honey, if you can't do it over the phone,
这事你就搞不定了 我们可不会为海莉买车
You can't do it, because we're not buying Haley a car.
-也是噢 -你明白就好
- Yeah. - Yeah.
好吧
Yeah.
那么
Well...
我还是去浴室待着好了
Well, I'm just gonna go to the bathroom.
菲尔·邓菲 你休想这样做
Phil Dunphy, don't you even dream of it.
克莱尔 我所有的朋友都在那个联赛里
Claire, all my friends are in that league.
-别人会以为我傻呢 -那又怎么样
- I'm gonna like an idiot. - So what?
我可是支付了高额的入会费
So I paid a huge entrance fee.
-有多高额 -也不是很高 一点点而已
- How huge? - Not huge. Tiny.
我的天哪 什么事情把她乐成这样
Oh, my goodness. How is she not cracking up there?
瞧她乐的
Listen to her.
不 我知道 不过你知道吗
No, I know, but do you know?
等等 她一个人待着呢
Wait a minute. She's alone.
然后呢
So?
她一个人待着呢
She's alone.
娘亲噢
Oh, my god.
我知道 你真该看看她的短裤
I know. You should see her pants.
我用彩信发给你好了
I'll text it to you.
好的 等等 别挂 我会发给你的
Oh, wait. Okay. Hold on. I'll send it.
噢耶 被逮着了吧
Ha! Aha! Aha! Busted!
索菲 我等会儿再打给你
Sophie, I have to call you back.
我就知道 我就知道你没法做到
I knew it. I knew you couldn't do it.
我告诉你我肯定笑到最后
I told you I'd outlast them.
-真没劲 -这是怎么了
- This sucks! - What's going on?
我来告诉你这是怎么了
I'll tell you what's going on.
爷赢了
I win.
汽车泡汤了 我得把汤姆·布拉德抛售了
Nobody gets a car, I dump Tom Brady,
长时间困扰我们的噩梦终结了
and our long amish nightmare is over.
我真的不敢相信
I can't believe you thought
你居然以为能战胜我们
you were gonna put one over on us.
我也不敢相信
I can't believe
他居然已经在上网了
that he's actually already on the internet.
认栽吧 孩子
Believe it, girl.
-你现在真的在上网吗 -是滴
- So, you're actually online right now? - Yep.
很好 那我不得不很遗憾地告诉你 老爹
Well, then I hate to break it to you, daddy,
你输了
but you lose.
-什么 -什么
- What? - What?
这才不是我的手机呢
This isn't my phone.
是我用一块肥皂刻成的
I carved it out of a bar of soap
然后又用记号笔给它上色
and colored it in with a marker.
菲尔 她居然用一块肥皂刻了部手机出来
Phil, she carved a telephone out of a bar of soap.
太激动鸟 我就要有车啦
I can't believe it! I'm getting a car!
真扯淡 我们居然被忽悠了一把
Holy crap. We've been shawshanked.
抱歉来晚了
Sorry about the delay.
因为新舞蹈室的规划一事耽误了
I was going over the plans for our new dance studio.
真棒
Wow.
那么 你们先自我介绍下吧
So, tell me about yourselves.
好的 我是一名律师
Uh, well, I'm a lawyer.
我们的申请人中有很多律师
Many of our applicants are attorneys.
当然
Of course.
你有什么出众的地方吗
What sets you apart?
我 我
Um, well, I --
我的白人名字叫塔克
While my white-man name is Tucker,
我有16分之一的彻罗基族血统
I am 1/16 Cherokee.
期望着孩子像雄鹰一般展翅高飞
Ready for child to soar like eagle.
我的天哪
Oh, god.
你们是怎么个说法
So, what are you saying?
你得不到汽车
You're not getting a car.
但是我赢了啊
But I won.
是的 但是我们之前从未想过你居然会赢
Yes, but we never thought you would.
然后呢
So?
然后 恭喜你的胜利
So, congratulations on your victory.
没人能夺走这份荣誉
Nobody can ever take that away from you.
言之有理
So true. Mm-hmm.
可是我在房间里
But I spent two days in my room
对着块肥皂自言自语了两天啊
talking to a bar of soap.
这不公平
It's not fair.
一点都不公平
It's totally not fair.
我们也义愤填膺
We're outraged.
我们不是好父母
Bad parenting.
可我们之前说好的啊
But we had a deal.
事后诸葛亮 事前猪一样
Which, in hindsight, was utter nonsense.
你们好啊
Hey.
我们讨厌比林斯利
We hated Billingsley.
那地方简直愚蠢至极
The place is so stupid. Ugh!
面试泡汤的是吧
You blew the interview, didn't you?
杀出一对拉拉
Lesbians.
其中一个还坐轮椅
In a wheelchair.
不会吧
Oh.
你还生我气呢
You still mad at me?
你说呢
You tell me.
这是什么
What is this?
我在想 我一直在诋毁哥伦比亚
I've been thinking if you said as much about America
如果你也像我那样诋毁美国 我早就气冒烟了
as I said about Colombia, I'd be plenty ticked off.
这弥补不了什么 只是
Doesn't make up for everything, but...
去哥伦比亚的旅行
A trip to Colombia?
我想看看你们的村庄 学习下你们的文化
I want to see your village, learn your culture.
我爱你
I love you.
毫无疑问无论你来自哪里我都爱你
I'm sure I'm gonna love where you come from.
杰 谢谢 谢谢 谢谢
Aw, Jay. Thank you, thank you, thank you.
他想去我的村庄 没门
No way he's going to my village.
我住在那的时候出过两次车祸
I was in two car accidents when I was living there.
两次都是撞上了一只山羊
Both times I hit a goat.
其中一次还伤得挺重
One was hurt pretty bad.
不过好在我后备箱里放着把铲子
But it was a good thing I had a shovel in the trunk.
族长预言过
The tribe builter fortold that
虽然我会与金毛男结合
though I lay with fire-haired man,
送子雄鹰会给我们
the giving hawk would bring us baby
玉米色肌肤的孩子
with her skin the color of sweet corn,
我们的族人称之为黄金之子
which my people call maize.
快别说了
Please stop.
好吧
Well, um...
知识就是她的养料
Knowledge is her sustenance,
就像那么多的玉米
like so much maize --
玉米这个词你应该记得住吧
which, you'll remember, means "Corn."
如果我是个单身父亲呢
What if I was a single dad?